你看，太不可思议了
Check it out,this is unbelievable!
乔伊已经闷气将近4分钟
Joey's been holding his breath for almost four minutes.
你想闷死我啊？
You trying to kill me?
菲比，我问你一件事 什么事？
-I want to ask you something. -What?
既然我要搬出去 你又这么美丽…
Since I'm moving out,and you're so beautiful...
我搬去跟你住如何？
how about I move in with you?
太好了，但是狄妮丝怎么办？
That would be great,but what do we do about Denise?
谁是狄妮丝？ 我的室友
-Who's Denise? -My roommate.
你有室友？ 对，狄妮丝，狄妮丝
Your roommate?Yes,Denise. Denise!
你干嘛这么神秘？ 这个狄妮丝可爱吗？
What is with the secrecy,Phoebe?What about Denise? She cute?
我们怎么会不知道你有室友？
How can you have a roommate that we don't know about?
也许是因为都没人在听我讲话 我一天到晚提起她，狄妮丝！
Because you never listen to what I say.I talk about her all the time. Denise!
瑞秋，我在想 我那里会多一个房间
I'm gonna have an extra room over at my place.
没错 你何不搬来跟我住？
-That's true. -Move in with me.
多好啊 我们可以熬夜谈心，看电影
We can stay up late talking,and watch movies.
你知道赤裸星期四的规定吧？
You know about naked Thursdays,right?
我还是自己找房子好了
Yeah,yeah. I think I'll find my own place.
我以为赤裸星期四 是我们的专利
Hey! I thought naked Thursdays was just our thing,man.
本集播出：“罗斯不认账”
The One With Ross' Denial
主演：珍妮佛安妮斯顿
寇妮考克斯阿奎特
丽莎库卓
麦特勒布兰
马修派瑞
大卫修蒙
你没办注销，瑞秋怎么说？
What did Rachel say when you told her you were still married to her?
那个啊，她还蛮平静的
Oh,that.She took it really well.
你没说对吧？ 没有
-You didn't tell her,did you? -No.
当然没有，因为你爱她
Because you're in love with her.
我并不爱她 她在为搬家的事难过
I am not in love with her. She was upset about having to move out.
所以我没说，免得她更不开心
If she knew we were still married,she'd have been more upset.
我只以朋友的身份安慰她
So I comforted her. As a friend.
什么叫安慰她？ 也没什么，我抱了抱她
You "comforted her"?Nothing. I just gave her a hug.
拥抱正是爱的表示
A classic sign of love,the hug.
也是友情的表现
It's also a sign of friendship.
在这里不是，痴情男
Not in your case,"Lovey Loverson."
那只是个拥抱
It was a hug. Okay?
一个单纯的拥抱
A simple hug.
我只是对朋友尽朋友的心意
I was a friend being a friend to a friend.
你太强调朋友了
Use the word "friend" more.
告诉我，你有没有闻她的头发
Did you,or did you not,smell her hair?
闻她的头发？如果有呢？
Smell her hair?What if I did?
九成的女性荷尔蒙散发自头部
Ninety percent of a woman's pheromones come out of her head.
所以女人都比较矮 好让男人在拥抱时爱上她们
That's why women are shorter.So that men will fall in love when they hug them.
拜托，你是科学家
Come on,Ross,you're a scientist.
我是以朋友的身分抱她
I was hugging her as a friend.
又不是我把脸埋进她的头发 她的头发很多，有一股…
It's not my fault her hair got in my face.She's got a lot of it,and it smells all... all...
椰子香
coconutty.
怎样？那不代表我对她有感觉 或许我是对椰子有感觉
What? It doesn't mean I have feelings for Rachel.Maybe it means I have feelings for coconuts.
好，随你怎么说
Okay,whatever you say
但你要小心 瑞秋的心情和你不同
but be careful. Rachel's not in the same place you are.
如果这个心情是指爱情 那她和我的心情一样
If the place you're referring to is being in love...she is in the same place as me,
因为我不是那个心情
because I am not in that place.
好，我听不懂
I didn't understand that.
或许因为你讲的是爱的秘语
Maybe that's because you were speaking the secret language of love.
刚才有你的电话 是谁？
-A guy just called for you. -Who was it?
我哪知道？ 可能是“麻烦你告诉他一声”？
I don't know. How about "Thanks for taking the message"?
等你搬进来 瑞秋的房间就空出来了
When you move in...Rachel's room will be empty.
要不要来讨论怎么利用？
Let's talk about what to do with it.
好啊 我想我们应该弄个漂亮的客房
I think we should have a beautiful guest room...
有红木雪橇床 床头桌上永远插着鲜花
with a mahogany sleigh bed and bedside tables with fresh flowers.
再摆张书桌放上留言卡 让客人表达他们的开心
And comment cards so people could tell us how great their stay was.
之类的，我还没有想太多
I really haven't thought about it that much.
我喜欢这个主意…当然喜欢
Well,I like that idea... obviously.
我在想或许可以弄个游戏房
I was thinking maybe... maybe it could be a game room.
我们可以买旧的游戏机
You can buy old arcade games,
像太空入侵者和小行星 只要2百元，是真正的街机，大的，大的
like Space lnvaders and Asteroids for $200. The real ones. The big,big,big ones!
不要
No.
你的意思是“天哪，钱德”
You mean "No" as in:"Gee Chandler"
“好有趣的主意” “我们先讨论再全盘否定”
"What an interesting idea. Let's discuss it before we reject it."
对不起，当然啦
I'm sorry.Of course I mean that
很有趣的主意 谈过了 但是不要
Interesting idea. Talk about it,But no.
就这样？
So that's it?
漂亮的客房不适合放游戏机
I just don't think arcade games go in a beautiful guest room...
漂亮的客房里会有很多古董
The beautiful guest room is gonna be filled with antiques.
所以小行星才适合 那是最古老的游戏
Which is why Asteroids is perfect. It's the oldest game.
你对漂亮的客房有什么意见？
What's wrong with a beautiful guest room?
我没有意见 尤其是我们认识的人
I'm not against it.Especially since everybody we know
都住在30秒远的路程之内
lives about 30 seconds away.
你在嘲笑我吗？
Are you mocking me?
我没有在嘲笑你 或是你漂亮的客房
No,I'm not mocking you or your beautiful guest room.
怎么了？
What's up
没事，莫妮卡和我吵架了
Monica and l had a stupid fight.
但你们还是要同居吧？ 我的广告今天出来了
You're still moving in together,right? My ad came out today.
“通缉令：女性室友，不抽烟，不丑”
"Wanted: Female roommate,nonsmoker,nonugly."
很好
Nice.
我想说在你之后 换个女室友会蛮有趣的
I figured it'd be more interesting to have a female roommate.
一个我可以学习 和我不一样的人
Someone I could learn from. Someone who's different than me.
谁和我最不一样？ 年过19的男人
And what's more different than me,a guy who's not 19...
还是19岁的女孩？
than a girl who is 19?
我可不是草包
Not just a hatrack,my friend.
菲比，我想问… 嘘…我正在忙
Phoebe,I have to ask you..I'm swamped right now.
你只是在发呆
You're just staring into space.
我想移动那支铅笔
I'm trying to move that pencil.
这支吗？ 成功了
-This one? -lt worked!
菲比，找房子真是恶梦
Phoebe,this whole apartment thing is a nightmare.
我租得起的地方都有怪胎室友 你看嘛
Anything I can afford comes with a roommate who is a freak. Look.
“通缉令：女性室友，不抽烟，不丑”
"Wanted: Female roommate,nonsmoker,nonugly."
可能是想跟女生讲电话的12岁小鬼
That's probably some 12-year-old kid trying to get girls to call.
没房子了，纽约都住满了
There's nothing. This city is full.
等等，这里有
Wait! Look at this!
“两房两卫，不得抽烟” “撒旦崇拜者亦可”
"Two bedroom,two bath. Must be nonsmoker. Satan worshipers okay."
可惜是在地下
Yeah,but it's on the ground floor.
瑞秋，你还在找房子？ 对，怎样？
-Rach,you still looking for a place? -Yeah,why?
好，我们博物馆有个华伦 要去参与挖掘工作2年
This guy,Warren,from the museum is going on a dig for two years.
他有个漂亮的家要转租 你有兴趣吗？
He's got this great place he needs to sublet. You interested?
听起来好棒 我愿意住华伦家，我爱华伦
Great! I'd love to live at Warren's. I love Warren!
等等，是他跟你要我的裸照吗
Oh,wait. Is he the guy that asked you for naked pictures of me?
没关系，反正他要走了
That doesn't matter,he won't be there!
谢谢你 别谢我
-Thank you! -Don't thank me.
要谢就谢那座火山几千年前爆发 毁灭却也保存了一整个文明遗迹
Thank the volcano that erupted thousands of years ago...killing,but perfectly preserving,an entire civilization.
这是华伦的电话
Here's Warren's number.
太好了，我现在就打给他 谢谢你
This is great. I'm gonna call him right now! Thank you!
好，快去吧
Okay,you go call him.
我看到了
I saw it.
我不知道你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我在说你知道却不肯承认的事
I'm talking about what you already know but won't admit.
你又爱上她了，你旧情复燃
You love her again. You re-love her.
我没有旧情复燃 真不敢相信 你就是不肯承认
I do not re-love her.I can't believe you won't just admit it.
总之你千万别做蠢事
Promise me you won't do anything stupid.
我们现在只是朋友 我为什么要做蠢事？
We're just friends now. Why would I do anything stupid?
房子已经租出去了 没希望了，我找不到房子了
The apartment is already subletted.It's hopeless. I'll never find anything.
你可以来跟我住 什么？
You can live with me.-What?
什么？
-What?!
怎样？
What?
天哪，你是说真的吗？
Are you serious?
我求之不得，太好了，谢谢你
I would love to live with you. That's great. Thank you.
有帮到你就好
I'm just glad I could help you out.
我真替你们高兴 这真是非常的不蠢
Wow,I'm so happy for you guys. This is so,so,not stupid.
罗斯，这对我太重要了
Ross,you have no idea what this means to me.
我差点就要流落街头 你救了我，你是我的英雄
I was gonna be homeless. You just saved me. You're my hero.
说英雄就太…好吧
Hero? I don't know. Well,all right.
我要去告诉莫妮卡 她的哥哥有多棒
I have to go tell Monica what a wonderful brother she has.
别这样
Oh,please.
你又有话要说了吧？
You're gonna say things now,aren't you?
没有，但是我告诉你
No. No,I won't.But I should tell you this.
我的室友狄妮丝就是这样
The same thing happened to my roommate,Denise.
她搬去跟一个暗地里没有跟她离婚的人住 他嘴上说不爱，其实很爱她
She moved in with a guy who was secretly married to her.He said he didn't love her,but he really did.
后来事情暴露 所以她才搬来跟我住
And it just blew up.And that's how she ended up living with me.
好吧，我骗你的
Okay,that's a lie.
你没有室友 狄妮丝
-You don't have a roommate. -Denise!
都没有人听我讲话
No one ever listens to me!
刚才很抱歉，我不需要游戏房
Listen,I'm sorry about before. I don't need a game room.
我以前没有女朋友才去打游戏
I only played those games because I couldn't get girls.
现在我有了…
Now I can get..
现在我有了你
Now I have you.
我并不是把你当成 或想成一件财产
No,not that I think I have you...or think of you as property in any sort of way.
我对女人… 别再说了钱德
I see women....Stop it,Chandler.
我也很抱歉
I'm sorry too.
真的？ 对，当然
-Really? -Yeah. Oh,yes.
我们不必弄一个客房 我们可以一起想要怎么利用
We can think of something to do with the room together.
好主意 要做到皆大欢喜很容易
Great idea. We can easily think of a way for us both to enjoy the room.
就是啊
Totally.
我们不必现在想 好
-We don't have to decide now. -Good.
不如来想想客厅要怎么变化
Let's think about changes we can make in the living room.
变化？
Changes?
对，我们得移动一些家具 来放我的椅子
We'll have to move some furniture to make room for my chair.
你要把躺椅搬过来？ 有问题吗？
You're bringing the Barcalounger over here?Is that a problem?
那是一组的，应该摆在一起
It's just that they're a set and should stay together.
那好，那我就都搬过来
That's cool. I'll bring them both over.
你是要它们离开老家
You're taking them away from their home.
好，我懂了，这里没我的东西 只有你的东西
I get it. I get nothing. Nothing here is mine. Everything is yours.
我早上起床就穿上你的衣服 然后去上班
I'll get up in the morning,put on your clothes and go off to work!
没错，这里只有我的东西 没有你的，这是我说的
Yeah,that's it. Everything will be mine. Nothing will be yours.
拜托！我是在讲躺椅
I'm talking about the Barcalounger.
它跟这里不搭，你要摆哪里？
It doesn't match. Where will it go?
游戏房里
In the game room!
你的椅子那么丑又不是我的错
It is not my fault your chairs are incredibly ugly.
好，我不搬椅子过来 我什么都不搬过来
That's fine.I won't bring the chairs. I won't bring anything!
我可不想破坏老奶奶家的格调
I wouldn't want to ruin the ambiance over here at grandma's place!
你的条件看起来很好 最后一个问题
Everything on your application looks really good.Just one last question.
你和你朋友 会不会常来这里狂欢聚会？
Will your friends be over here,partying and hanging out?
放心，我不太爱玩
Don't worry. I'm not a party girl.
别想都不想就说 我要你想清楚再答
Don't just be blurting stuff out.I want you to really think about your answers.
你不必找室友了 你好，我要住在这里
Call off the roommate search. Hi. I'll be living here.
别理他，他很想住进来 但我不会选他
Ignore him. He's just some guy who wants the apartment.But he's not going to get it.
你干嘛把浴帘拿掉？
You took down the shower curtain?
那个东西很危险
That thing was a hazard!
我很注重安全
I'm very safety conscious.
我正在清一些空间给你 谢谢
I was just clearing some space for your stuff.Thanks.
但我刚去找莫妮卡 她和钱德大吵一架不同居了
But listen,Monica and Chandler had a big fight and they're not moving in.
什么叫不同居了？ 他们还是要同居吧？
What do you mean,not moving in? They're still moving in,right?
不，他们为了怎么利用空房 大吵一架
No,they just had a big blowout over what to do with my room.
就为了一个烂房间？
Over a stupid room?
我也有点替他们可惜 却又很高兴不必搬过来了
I feel kind of bad for them,but now I don't have to move in here!
没错，这一点的确很棒
Oh,no. Yeah,that part's great.
你们两个是在吵什么？
What's all this about you guys fighting?
真的就为了一个房间？ 真是太傻了
Is this really over a room?That is so silly.
罗斯，我们自己可以摆平 显然不行
-We can handle this. -Apparently not.
我不能坐视两个我关心的人 为了这么傻的事伤感情
And I can't stand by and watch two people I care about so much be hurt by something that is so silly.
别再傻了
Enough of the silliness.
你叫她别傻啊
Tell her to stop being silly.
好
Okay
双方都有理
Two very good points.
我认识你们两个很久了
I've known you both a long time.
你们在一起之后 比以前快乐一百万倍
And I've never seen either of you one-millionth as happy as you've been since you got together.
你们真的要为了一个房间 放弃这一切？
Do you really want to throw that all away over a room?
多傻啊
That is so silly.
什么比较重要 爱情还是傻气？
What's more important,love...or silliness?
我们喜欢傻气 但面对爱情也会心软
Well,we are fond of the silliness.But we also have a soft spot for the love.
爱是万灵药 欢笑才是吧？
-Love is the best medicine. -That's "laughter."
你为什么这样？ 我不知道
-Why do you do it? -I don't know.
钱德，你想跟莫妮卡住吧？
Now,Chandler,you want to live with Monica,right?
对
Yeah,I do.
莫妮卡，你想跟钱德住吧？ 对
And,Mon,you want to live with Chandler?Yes.
很好，口头契约 在纽约州有约束力
Good！A verbal contract is binding in the state of New York!
我听说你在找房子
So I understand you're looking for a place?
不，我不搬了
No,I'm staying put.
我本来打算找你来我家住
I was going to offer you my apartment.
为什么？你要去哪里？
Why? Where you going?
我不知道
I don't know.
瑞秋
Rachel
说了你一定不信 钱德和莫妮卡又要同居了
You won't believe it.Monica and Chandler are moving in again.
真是太好了… 对他们来说，对吧？
That's great news,right? I mean,for them,right?
不过好处是我们又能当室友了
But on the bright side,we get to be roommates again.
是啊，关于这件事…
Yeah. You know,about that....
我很感谢你主动提议，但是…
I really appreciate your offer to let me move in and everything...but
你不觉得会很怪吗？
don't you think it'll be weird?
为什么？为…为什么会怪？
Why? Why would it.... Why would it be weird?
因为我们的过去
Well,you know,because of us.Because of our history.
不会 不会吗？
No!No,
不会，除非我们还余情未了
no!It would only be weird if we were still in "that place."
你还余情未了吗？
Are you still in that place?
一点也没有 很好，我也没有
-No,not at all. -Good. Me neither.
那就没问题了 我们只是刚好是室友的朋友
So it's not a problem.We're just two friends who happen to be roommates.
好，但我们迟早会约会
Okay,but eventually you and I will be dating.
是吗？
Really? We are?
是啊，我会有男朋友 你会有女朋友
Yeah. I'll have a boyfriend and you'll have a girlfriend.
那太好了
That'd be great.
不过如果你觉得无所谓 我们就想一套方法
But if you think it'll be okay,we'll just work out a system.
就像大学时代 我在门上挂个牌子
It'll be like in college. I'll hang a sign on the door:
“暂且回避，正在蜜运中”
"Come back later. I'm getting lucky."
我想都没想过
Yeah,I didn't think of that.
你们确定要住在一起？
So are you sure about this whole moving-in thing?
这是很大的进展，急什么呢？
It's a really big step. And what's the rush?
真好笑
That's very funny.
他在装傻 因为他知道我们喜欢傻气
He's being silly because he knows we enjoy the silliness.
我是说真的，你们想想 你搬进来
No,I'm serious. Think about it. You move in.
你们为了游戏房的事吵架 接下来就会分手
You start fighting over game rooms. Next thing you know,you break up.
罗斯，你说得对 吵那种架很蠢
It was just a stupid fight about a room.
一点也不蠢
There are no stupid fights!
重点不是房间 而是房间代表什么
This isn't about the room.This is about what the room represents.
很不幸的 这个房间会毁了你们
And unfortunately,this room could destroy you!
我没那么担心 我也是
-I'm not so worried. -Me neither.
好吧，这是你们的人生
Fine. It's your life!
我只是不想看到你们分手 你们要是同居就会分手
I just don't want to see you break up.Which you will do if you move in together.
但你们想这样，我也没办法
But if that's what you want,there's nothing I can do.
不要同居
Don't do it!
你还是想搬进来吧？ 当然
-You still want to move in together? -Of course.
罗斯没吓到你？ 吓得我死也不敢跟他住
Ross didn't scare you?Scared me out of wanting to live with him.
我给你看个东西 好
-I gotta show you something. -Okay.
天哪，一个正方形的人被杀了
Oh,my God! Someone's killed Square Man!
我觉得躺椅可以放这里
The Barcalounger can go here.
你可以看电视，离厨房又够近 真贴心
You can see the TV,and it's still walking distance to the kitchen.Oh,that's so sweet.
我也有事要说 好
I want to show you something too.
你知道道路会合的标志吧？
You know those big road signs that say "merge"?
我想我们可以弄一个挂在床头
I thought we could get one of those signs and hang it over our bed.
因为你和我就是那样 合而为一
Because that's you and I together."Merge!"
天哪，我好喜欢
-I love that!
真的？ 才怪
-Really?"No!"
我发现你在我床上 你怎么会在那里？
I found you in my bed How'd you wind up there?
你真是个谜，小黑卷毛男
You are a mystery  Little black curly hair
小黑卷毛…小黑卷毛男
Little black,little black,little black…Little black curly hair
如果想通过电子邮件收到我的演出讯息 请捐钱给我，让我买电脑
If you want to receive e-mails about my upcoming shows...please give me money so I can buy a computer.
其他人呢？
Where are the other guys?
莫妮卡和钱德在忙
Well,Monica and Chandler are occupied.
吵架？ 不，是忙别的
-Fighting? -The other thing.
真高兴他们能和好
It's great they worked things out.
谁也别想拆散他们，对吧？
There's no breaking them up,is there?
可以跟你借钥匙去配一把吗？
Can I borrow the key to your house so I can go make a copy?
当然可以，拿去 谢谢
-Here. -Thank you.
你确定吗？ 配了钥匙就不能反悔了
Are you sure? Once I make a copy,there's no turning back.
我确定 趁我改变心意前快去吧
Yeah,I'm sure. Now get out of here before I change my mind.
罗斯，跟瑞秋住真的好吗？
You think moving in with Rachel is a good idea?
我也在摇摆不定
I've been back and forth.
也许你应该摆回去
Well,maybe you should go back.
瑞秋搬进去 不知不觉间你们就又复合了
She moves in,and before you know it...you're right where you don't want to be,back together
应该不会 她已经在谈交男朋友的事
I don't think so. She's already talking about dating other guys.
不会有结果的
That's not going to work out.
她会哭着回家，你会告诉她
She'll come home all weepy...and you'll be telling her,
“没关系，你会找到好男人”
"Oh,that's okay. You'll find someone."
接着，“砰”！她找到了你
And then,bam! She finds you!
也许你说得对
Maybe you're right.
她绝对会再爱上你 这样你也愿意吗？
Ross,she is definitely gonna fall in love with you again.Is that what you want?
我愿意吗？ 是的
Is that what I want?Yes.
她来了，我只是想让你活着轻松点
Here she comes. I'm gonna make your life much easier.
那间店关门了，改天再配吧 或是别配了
The place was closed,so I'll copy it later.Or not.
瑞秋，你就搬来跟我住嘛
Why don't you move in with me?
乔伊 等等…
Whoa,Joey!
瑞秋，我知道赤裸星期四 把你吓跑了，但是…
Look,I know I scared you with that whole naked-Thursdays thing...but
我们也可以不那样子
we don't have to do that.
搬到对面确实比较轻松
It would be easier to move across the hall.
慢着 除非你想改成赤裸星期三
Unless you're thinking about naked Wednesdays.
你不喜欢星期四，那就挑一天
Thursday's clearly not good for you. Pick a day!
请进，谢谢你再跑一趟
Come on in. Thanks for coming back.
有很多人想租，但我经过筛选
There's a lot of people interested in the room.But I've narrowed it down,
你是最后人选之一 太好了
and you're one of the finalists.-Great!
在做决定之前 我想确定我们合得来
-Before I decide...I want to be sure our personalities match.
所以我发明了一个小测验
So I made up a little test.
我说一个词 你就说出第一个联想
I'll say a word,and you say the first thing that comes to mind.
没问题 好，那我们开始
-I can do that. -Okay,here we go.
枕头 打架
-Pillow. -Fight.
很好
Very good.
好，“G”？-丁字裤？
"G."-String?
非常好
-Excellent!
好…狗
Doggy.
猫？ 很抱歉
-Kitten? -Sorry!
就差那么一点点，再见
So close,though. Bye-bye!